WILLIAMS AJAYI BALOGUN

Frontend Developer

- https://linkedin.com/in/williamsbalogun
- https://github.com/willhemz
- **y** https://twitter.com/ihemzDev?t=r4MTSP-zBFcBsPiMtHAw5A&s=09
- ⊠ williamsbalogun49@gmail.com
- **Q** Lagos, Nigeria.

SUMMARY

Experienced Frontend Developer with proficiency in utilizing high end stacks in creating quality websites and web applications. Open-source contributor, facilitator, not shy of tough tasks, ably solid in engaging and collaborating with other developers, designers, product managers.

EDUCATION

Obafemi Awolowo University

2016 - 2022

B.Sc. Mechanical Engineering (CGPA 4.03/5.00)

Class Rank: Top 10%

Undergraduate Research – "Numerical Study on the Heat Transfer Enhancement in Straight and Wavy Microchannel Heat Sinks Under Pulsating CuO-Al2O3/H2O Hybrid Nanofluid"

EXPERIENCE

HNG Frontend Intern at Zuri

October – December (2022)

- Collaborated with several Developers (Frontend, Backend), DevOps, Designers and Product Manager to building web solutions to problems. Most notable are:
 - <u>https://coverly.hng.tech</u>
 - <u>https://streetrates.hng.tech</u>

Freelance Developer

2020 - 2022

- Worked with several clients and developers in building, modifying and restructuring their web sites and web applications.

- Volunteered and collaborated in the development of a shopping websites for a startup company (https://umecarts.com)
- Volunteered and collaborated in the development of a website containing designs catalogs for Delta Computers & Stores Ltd (https://newdcstech.com)

Staff 2012 – 2016

- Worked in the training department to tutor trainees on the use of Microsoft Office Applications and also helped them boost their typing skills.
- Was Head of Training in 2013 through 2014. Managed trainees' welfare.
- Worked in the operations department as a Graphics Designer. Created designs (booklets, magazines, logo, ID cards, complementary cards, calendars, shirt designs etc.) for individuals, brands, schools, organizations and government bodies etc.
- Was Head of Operations in 2015. Managed all jobs from our clients and ensured tasks are duly assigned and deadlines were met. Ensured clients got satisfaction from jobs delivered.

STACKS

- JavaScript
 TypeScript
 jQuery
 TypeScript
 - React Redux Tailwind Bootstrap
- Sass
 Firebase
 Jasmine
 Jest

TOOLS

- Git Terminal Github Netlify
- Vercel
 Slack
 Linear
 Discord
- TwitterZoom

PROJECTS

Collaborative Projects

- https://streetrates.hng.tech
- https://coverly.hng.tech
- https://newdcstech.com
- https://umecarts.com